<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zachary M. Johnson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zachary M. Johnson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:45:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Lifting State to the URL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/benefits-of-lifting-state-to-the-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 18:45:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/benefits-of-lifting-state-to-the-url/</guid>
      <description>I recently found myself needing to lift some parts of my application state into the URL. I usually default to use some state management solution in my web projects, and I am a huge fan of Zustand. However, there comes a time when using this type of state management alone may not provide all the desired functionality.&#xA;Why Lift State Normally, when using something like Redux, the global store lives in memory within the JavaScript runtime of your application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Data Migrations in Contentful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/streamlining-data-migrations-in-contentful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 18:45:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/streamlining-data-migrations-in-contentful/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I completed a large data migration on the PhotoVoice Japan website. The purpose of this migration was to clean up existing content models and utilize Contentful’s locales feature to allow for cleaner and more efficient multi-language support. Thanks to Contentful’s use of multiple Environments within a project Space, this migration was quite straightforward.&#xA;Cloning your Existing Environment Fortunately, Contentful offers a very generous free &amp;ldquo;Intro&amp;rdquo; space license. Under the Intro license we are allowed three environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Career I launched my professional career in February, 2021 at the software consultancy Atomic Object. While at Atomic I have worked on multiple projects with a variety of tech stacks, including React/Node and Angular/.NET Core projects. In addition to this site, my writings can be found on the Atomic Object blog, known as Spin.&#xA;Interests My technical interests include all things web development, Bitcoin and Austrian economics. When away from the computer I enjoy running and balance sports.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
